Guide to the Soil Conservation Service Prince William County aerial photograph collection, 1953-1981
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Soil Conservation Service Prince William County aerial photograph collection
1953-1981
C0271
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
6.5 linear ft. (8 boxes)
The collection consists of hundreds of black and white prints taken by the United States Department of Agriculture's Soil Conservation Service between 1953 to 1981 of Prince William County, Virginia.
United States. Dept. of Agriculture. Soil Conservation Service.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor unknown.
Historical Information
Passed in 1938, the Soil Conservation District Law of Virginia enabled individuals within Virginia to be able to direct programs with the goal of addressing and solving any conservation issues present in their communities. Prince William makes up one of forty-seven conservation districts in Virginia.
Prince William County's Soil and Conservation District, which is led by a five-member board, aims to protect and enhance the land belonging to the county. It also has many programs setup with that educate youth and adults on proper conservation techniques. The District also play a large role in water quality improvement throughout the county.
Scope and Content
The collection is predominantly comprised of black and white prints of Prince William County. Most of the prints are 11x11 inches in size. Also included are map indexes which include detailed flight path grids which correspond to a majority of the prints. Maps like the ones included in this collection can be utilized in a number of different ways ranging from educational purposes to land development projects.
Arrangement
Organized by flight path.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds other collections that include aerial photography of Northern Virginia, including the, the, and the.
Bibliography
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Virginia, Northern--Photographs.
Document Types:
Aerial photographs.; Maps.; Virginia, Northern--Photographs.
Contents List
  - Flight Paths 1-10, March 31, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Out of Boundry Flights, March 31, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Flight Paths 8-10, 12, 14, December 8, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Flight Paths 1, 4-8, 11, 13, February 10, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Flight Paths 1-3, 8, 9, 17-19, December 31, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Flight Path 11, April 9, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Flight Path 12, December 18, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Flight Path 13, February 10, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Flight Path 14, December 31, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Flight Path 6, February 10, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Flight Path 7, February 10, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Flight Path 8, February 10, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Flight Path 4, February 10, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Flight Path 11, April 9, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Flight Path 10, December 8, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Flight Path 9, March 29, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Flight Path 5, February 10, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Flight Path 1, March 29, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Flight Path 2, March 29, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Flight Path 3, March 29, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Unnumbered Flight, June 30, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture Photograph Envelopes, Circa 1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture Map Indexes To Photographs, 1954, 1974, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)